### ISTVAN GERCSAK

Address Apartment 48 Online Presence LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/istyangercsak/

Winter Garden,
Pearse Street,
Dublin 2

GitHub
Personal site
Personal site
Blog
https://github.com/lstvanGercsak
https://istvan-the-qa.com/
https://istvan-the-qa.com/blog

+353894473833 FreeCodeCamp https://www.freecodecamp.org/istvangercsak

### **SUMMARY:**

I am highly engaged in my profession with my 6 years of experience in the software testing field. I like to do it and I always want to be better, therefore, I committed next to self-improvement. My experiences stand for manual and automation testing, proven work experience in an agile environment, programming skills, widespread technical and business knowledge.

### IT SKILLS:

Technical General DEV ISTQB certified (Foundation) Jenkins, CI Agile development (Scrum) Java, Junit, TestNG BDD(Cucucmber) SQL. Mongo DB Waterfall development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery Gauge **PostgreSQL** Jira Bootstrap, Materialize Robot Framework Amazon AWS servers Putty Python, Flask, Django XML and JSON Test automation Heroku Version control, Git, GitHub Selenium Webdriver (Java, C#, Python)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

02/12/2019 - Present

# Axa Ireland, QA Test Analyst (Contractor), Ireland

(Ireland biggest Insurance Company)

- Test Analyst (50%) and Test Automation Engineer (50%) role in a scrum team and in the Test Automation team
- Used technologies: Visual studio, C#, Azure Cloud, Oracle Database

14/05/2019 - 30/11/2019

### OpenJaw Technologies, QA Automation Engineer, Ireland

(OpenJaw Technologies provide solutions for the global flight industry all around the world.)

- QA responsibilities:
  - I work with two Developer teams and collaborate with other teams (DevOps team, Architect team)
  - I use Jira for Bug tracking and write test scenarios
- Test Automation responsibilities:
  - I create new Test Automation framework and Test Automation Analysis document
    - I create pilot project from scratch with: Maven, Gauge, Selenium, Java
- Manager responsibilities:
  - I interview the new QA candidates
  - o I report the QA side to the costumer in every week about the actual process
  - I introduce the ongoing QA tasks and give update during the weekly team meetings

10/2017 - 29/03/2019

### MetLife, Test Consultant (Contractor), Ireland

(Our project was an insurance payment tracking system. It was an experimental project and it was created from scratch thus it is changing a lot)

- Design manual test cases in BDD format and execute them
- Find bugs in the software and report it in Jira
- GUI Test automation pilot:
  - Custom made Jenkins servers by me, Cucumber and TestNG reports, Test automation framework used Selenium Webdriver with Java

### 05/2016 - 08/2017

## IP Systems Ltd., QA Test Engineer, Hungary

(The IP Systems Ltd. operates in the energy market, mostly in the gas and electricity field. It develops IT platforms for the participant of the market depends on the customer needs. The products are very wide-spreaded)

- Functional testing web based software
- Communication with the costumers and the Product Owner
- Ensure the quality of the actual projects (with tests and advises):
  - Energy Data Clearing House (6 months)
  - Multidimensional auction system (3 months)
  - Trading-IP (5 months)
- Prepare test environments:
  - o Build test environment with Jenkins jobs
  - Prepare the test environment to test (upload date, prepare test cases, check the log files)
- Managing release processes
- Participation every steps of the SDLC
  - Sprint planning and Scrum meetings
  - Supervise the release process
- Write automation tests (Selenium WebDriver with Java)

#### 01/2016 - 05/2016

# Aegon Hungary Composite Insurance Company Ltd., Junior IT Business Analyst, Hungary

- Writing functional specifications and user guides
- Supervising the daily and monthly closure
- Assistance with the satellite systems
- · Cooperation with the programmers

#### 05/2014 - 12/2015

## Aegon Hungary Composite Insurance Company Ltd., Junior Tester, Hungary

(The Aegon insurance company is one of the biggest insurance company in Hungary. Its CRM system handles the life and non-life insurance contracts. Its software used by the insured people and administrators as well.)

- Manual testing the business processes in the CRM insurance portfolio systems
- Maintain & Support the actual systems and projects
- Handling the incoming error tickets (prioritization, management)
- Working closely with the developers and the business analysts.

#### **EDUCATION:**

### 2019

- 01/2019 01/2020
  - Full Stack Software Development Diploma (Code Insitute Bootcamp)
    - <u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Git & GitHub, JavaScript, jQuery, Jasmine, API, TDD, Python, Flask, Data Management, SQL, Mongo DB, Agile development

# 2018

- ISTQB Advanced Level Automation Test Engineer Course
- ISTQB Advanced Level Test Manager Course

# 2016

- ISTQB-Foundation level certification

### 2011 - 2014

- University of Debrecen, Debrecen, Hungary
  - o Business Informatics Bachelor Degree